Every dog has his day.
Reservoir Dogs is a crime, thriller film directed by Quentin Tarantino.
A botched robbery indicates a police informant, and the
pressure mounts in the aftermath at a warehouse.
Crime begets violence as the survivors -- veteran Mr.
White, newcomer Mr.
Orange, psychopathic parolee Mr.
Blonde, bickering weasel Mr.
Pink and Nice Guy Eddie -- unravel.
Mr. White / Larry Dimmick, played by Harvey Keitel.
Mr. Orange / Freddy Newandyke, played by Tim Roth.
Mr. Blonde / Vic Vega, played by Michael Madsen.
"Nice Guy" Eddie Cabot, played by Chris Penn.
Mr. Pink, played by Steve Buscemi.
Joe Cabot, played by Lawrence Tierney.
Reservoir Dogs is a 1992 American independent heist film written and directed
by Quentin Tarantino in his feature-length directorial debut.
It stars Harvey Keitel, Tim Roth, Chris Penn, Steve Buscemi, Lawrence Tierney, Michael Madsen, Tarantino,
and Edward Bunker as diamond thieves whose heist of a jewelry store goes terribly wrong.
Kirk Baltz, Randy Brooks, and Steven Wright also play supporting roles.
The film incorporates many motifs that have become Tarantino's hallmarks: violent
crime, pop culture references, profanity, and nonlinear storytelling.
The film is regarded as a classic independent film and a cult film.
Although controversial at first for its depictions of violence and heavy use of profanity,
Reservoir Dogs was generally well received, and the cast was praised by many critics.
Despite not being heavily promoted during its theatrical run, the film became a modest
success in the United States after grossing $2.9 million against its scant budget.
It achieved higher popularity after the success of
Tarantino's next film, Pulp Fiction (1994).
A soundtrack was released featuring songs used in the
film, which are mostly from the 1970s.
It was named "Greatest Independent Film of All Time" by the British film magazine
Empire, which in 2008 also named it the 97th-greatest film ever made.
The film explores themes of escape, jewelry, psychopath, traitor, ear.
The tone is intense.